Next, let's learn how to make the tail of the fish.
For the tail of the fish, first, we need to use the one we taught in the first video.
Because the tail of the fish is relatively close to the body,
we need to move the tail a little bit to the inside, and then a little bit to the bottom,
so that it forms a relatively close state.
After that, we select these two sides, and then move.
In the process of moving, press the SHIFT key to move along the level or vertical direction.
We can move a little more, move to the knee position.
Next, we are going to do the tail of the fish.
To make it easier to use,
we can select the back panel,
and then rotate it here.
Select the Y-axis, and then the back center line.
Rotate it into a flat state.
Then use the rectangle tool to click and drag the mouse in the 2D window,
to create an equal width with the skirt.
Then the length, we can use the 2D scale to draw a length panel.
After creating, select this panel and press CTRL D to create a symmetrical panel.
Then copy and paste a group as the back panel.
If the width of the back panel is relatively large,
you can manually adjust it.
Then press SHIFT F to open the arrangement point,
and arrange these four panels in the corresponding position.
Then use the rectangle tool to put the top and bottom panels together,
and the sides are also sewed together.
After putting them together,
we can see that the whole thing looks like a traditional skirt.
Next, we are going to use the extension tool to open the panel.
In the Edit panel tool group,
we can find the extension tool.
It is in the second column.
After selecting the extension tool,
click on the top center point,
and then click on the bottom center point.
After forming a fold line with the arrow,
this fold line can be opened to both sides.
To the appropriate position, click on the mouse,
then the bottom panel is opened.
After opening, it is like a fan shape.
The fabric of the panel will be more and more,
so there will be some folds.
After creating the extension reference line,
select the left and right sides of this line,
then move the mouse,
it will only go along one side.
If you select this line,
it will open to both sides at the same time.
After opening the fold line,
we will find that the part where it is crossed
is the starting point of our extension.
It is a bit hard,
so here we will convert it to the starting point.
In the 2D window,
we will separate the panel a little bit.
If there is a place to add a fan line,
remember to check it and add it.
If we want to make it tighter at the knee,
we can put these two lines below,
so that both points are a little bit inward.
Now we can see that the position of the fan line
is created by some folds.
So we need to select this line and right-click to change the length.
The direction must be selected on both sides,
which is both.
Then we need to set the length
to the same length as the bottom panel of the top panel.
If you think there are not enough folds in the bottom panel,
we can continue to open this panel.
But there is one thing you need to pay attention to.
For example, the width of our extension is relatively large.
Because the point in the middle is not very smooth now,
there will be a relatively obvious angle.
So after sewing,
the top of the clothes looks like it has been pulled up.
So we need to adjust this point.
First of all, we need to convert it to a free curve point.
Then it is more difficult to adjust using the editor tool.
So we need to use the editor curve point tool.
First, delete the excess curve point.
Then we can keep two curve points that are used to pass.
While adjusting this curve,
we need to ensure that the curve is smooth.
There is no strange bulge.
Second, we need to ensure that the corner on the side is always a straight corner.
Let me show you here.
Let's go back to just now.
If these corners are all sharp corners,
have you seen that there is a missing piece in the middle?
If we insist on sewing it up in the case of a missing piece,
then it can't be made into a flat corner.
If you sew it directly like this,
it looks like it has been pulled up.
And the curve in the middle,
we try not to make it a particularly curved or particularly convex curve.
Try to go through it as smoothly as possible.
Then you can adjust it according to your own needs.
And our cut is not the one I'm trying to make.
This is a top-stitch.
Have you ever tried a top-stitch?
This is a small cut without any seam.
Look at the shape.
This is a cut with a curve.
This is a shape with only one fold.
This is a Top-stitch.
We need to adjust the curve.
We can do this with the double-sided tape,
so if we do this different to the top-stitch,
the top-stitch is going to be in the middle,
and there isn't any seam.
So, the curve starts from the top.
When we are done,
we are done with the top-stitch.
Then we can go back to the other side.